VALENTIN-MARIO PARASCHIV

Full-Stack Developer

London, United Kingdom

mariovparaschiv@gmail.com | +44 7752247152 <u>marioparaschiv.com</u> <u>github.com/marioparaschiv</u> linkedin.com/in/marioparaschiv

Summary

Highly motivated self-taught individual who loves working in a fast paced and pressurized environment.

I have over 5 years of hands-on experience with many languages, libraries, tools, and technologies, along with 1½ years of experience mentoring and teaching these technologies.

Recently have used my passion for technology and coding by guiding and teaching children to program their own projects using various programming languages and concepts ranging from JavaScript to C#.

Skills

Personal Skills

Active Listening, Adaptivity, Communication Skills – written and verbal, Compassion and Empathy, Patience, Gentle, Positive, and uplifting attitude along with a heavy personal interest in programming and problem-solving.

Technical Skills

I primarily specialise in **Node.js**, **TypeScript**, **Go**, **React**, **MongoDB**, **PostgreSQL**, **Express.js**, **and Next.js**.

Languages: JavaScript (5 years), HTML (5 years), CSS (5 years), TypeScript (4 years), Go (3 years),

Objective C (3 years), SCSS (3 years), Kotlin (1 year), Swift (1 year)

Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, Solid.js, Astro, Svelte, Tailwind CSS, Post CSS, SASS/SCSS, Express.js,

Fastify, Electron, Puppeteer, Gin, Gorm and many more REST frameworks and front-end libraries...

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Firebase, SQLite, MySQL

Runtimes: Node.js, Deno, Bun

Design: Figma, Canva, Adobe Photoshop

CI/CD: GitHub Actions, CircleCI

Tooling: AWS, Docker, Rollup, Webpack, Vite, swc, npm, pnpm, yarn

Version Control: Git, GitHub, Git Lab

Experience

Programming Tutor

Code Ninjas

Programming Tutor

Code Ninjas

August 2022 – September 2023 Borehamwood, Hertfordshire June 2022 – August 2022 North Finchley, London

- Taught and mentored children through a curriculum of game-based coding, using the programming languages JavaScript, C++, Java, and Python.
- I applied my expertise in software development to deliver tools that automate and offload tasks, leading to an increase in overall productivity of ~15%.
- Used teamwork in all aspects to educate and advocate the use of programming in the real world by breaking down concepts into small and easy-to-understand components, leading to an increase in interest from children learning these concepts.
- Demonstrated presentation and facilitation skills in leading summer camp programmes with sessions of up to 30 children in various technical disciplines such as algorithms, OOP (object-oriented programming), and functional programming.
- Drove an increase of close to 20% in organic sign-ups to the education centre through engaging prospective families in 'taster' sessions.
- Implemented the use of many tools such as CodeCombat, Micro:Bit, Microsoft MakeCode, Lego SPIKE, and many other tools aiding in the education of coding and STEM for pre-teens that are too young to take part in the game-based coding curriculum with the aim of widening the business' target audience and increasing customer retention for larger families.
- Ensured the safety of children by enforcing certain health and safety regulations as per the rules and procedures of the education facility.

Technical Software and Hardware Support Intern

Barnet and Southgate College

Wood Street, London Feb 2022 – June 2022

- Solved a broad range of file access issues by configuring Group Policy user groups correctly on a per-directory basis resulting in a 100% drop in issues related to denied file access in software products made by Microsoft and Adobe.
- Diagnosed and repaired faulty computers by isolating the issue to a singular hardware component allowing repair of a singular component instead of a complete unit replacement, leading to an increase of 10% overall revenue.
- Solved numerous issues, bugs, and failures with machines by reimagining them, causing a 70%

decrease in future support tickets from the same user leading to a significant increase in productivity for both the support team and user.

• Improved fault tolerance for various computer functionality by restricting configuration of Windows resulting in 20% less support inquiries.

Education

Barnet and Southgate College

Sept 2022 – Jul 2024

BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma in Information Technology

Grade

D*D*D* (Distinction*, Distinction*)

Achievements

Class Representative

Barnet and Southgate College

Sept 2021 - Jul 2022

BTEC Level 2 Extended Certificate in Information Technology

Grade

DD (Distinction, Distinction)

Achievements

Double Grade Distinction Award

Class Representative

Barnet and Southgate College

Sept 2020 - Jul 2021

GCSE

Business

English

Mathematics